welcome barbecue pit boys calm
today we're growing up some cheap barbecue beef roasted
to fit and are real easy
to do now what do I mean by cheap beef
roast what I have here is a cut
from the cattle that's called the eye around and
compared to rib roasts or ribeye
roast it's a lot cheaper
right it's probably one-third the cost
and this is the whole I round that we got from
the butcher and it's been untrimmed
it's really not ready for the typical grocery store meat counter
yet right what the butcher will do is clean these up real
good so there's a no fat pretty much what's the level on the
whoops the main thing about this is extremely lean very
lean in fact look at that there's no marbling there's no
fat it's a real difficult piece of beef to cook a conventional way
in the oven right the idea here is when
we cook these we want to maintain or retain as much moisture as we can in
the rows now to do that there are a number of
ways and our first roast here we're going to hit with some beef marinade
or some beef broth right
it's a beef
stock and it has some flavorings like little salt maybe some garlic's
pepper you choose your favorite beef broth to do
this now I have here an injector right
it's an ax meat injector you've seen these
before and so we're going to take a syringe
and inject the roast half a dozen times or
just
like that now we're injecting a ton warm moisture
in this rose because like I said
at the beginning the only way to eat these Rose
is full of moisture
right you don't want
them to dry out all right now we've injected that piece of roast
and it's weighing about three and a half pounds or so and
we're putting on an off the shelf Brook
and choose your favorite beef brokenness
simple
enough we're adding a layer and flavor of
with the injection of the beef broth on the
inside this is going to be good
all
right chief gross number one is prep
now
let's try a different
here we've got some
garlic and we're going to do the old garlic Club right
and garlic goes really
well with beef you should know
that in fact they're the best of the beef most often have garlic
right so we're just going to cut some slivers of the
clove here and made a hole with a knife
and we're going to plug we're going to force that garlic clove right
down inside so as it cooks we're going to have plenty of nice garlic sleep
now again as you can see how lean these roasts are alright
if you just threw this in a conventional oven
and cooked it for you know an hour hour and a half or whatever
trust me it'd be too tough to
eat it's a beautiful piece
of meat but you need to roast it real slow
low and
slow low
temperature this will help again maintain all the juiciness inside
this roast you cook it hot and fast like some some chefs do it
ain't going to work
don't believe the BS
right all right we've seasoned this roast with some
SPG right some salt and pepper
so cheap beef roast number two is prep
now let's do the third rows
here I have some barbecue sauce right
and I'm going to spread it all over this roast
all sides we're using one of our barbecue sauce
recipes you can check it out or use your
alright
cheap barbecue beef roast number three is done
now the
next rows we're going to do
a pepper roast so we've got some bell peppers roasting directly
over the fire and and we're going to inject this one as well so
we're going to grab more of our beef wok here and inject
this roast get it right down inside
you might hit its up six eight times whatever your pleasure
right this is good
again the combination of the injection right
and cooking low and slow or a low temperature
we produce a moist and tender roast beef
you got it right
now we're going to add some more
seasoning here we've got our SPG and
like I said before you can use salt and pepper
your favorite seasoning get it all over this
rose now before somebody asks why do you keep all the fat on the
roast all right well we want again use it as a barrier for the moisture on the inside
you keep all the fat
on there it's going to help maintain the juiciness of this roast
all right the
peppers have been roasted
just blackened up a bit on the outside pick up some
of the flavor and we'll place the peppers with some garlic on some heavy-duty aluminum foil
all right we're going to cover this
roast
now when this pepper roast is done
it'll be full of that bell pepper
flavor wonderful flavor
going to
now we'll throw some onions in there
again all of this is going to help keep this roast moist
and we're going to cook it again at a lower
temperature so we're going to maximize the
tenderness now we've added again some more beef
cloth in there and I
we kind of kind of steam it for a
I'm telling it you like pepper roast you definitely got to check this
wrap it up
and you're going to need to double wrap this so
grab another piece of aluminum
and wrap it
you
now of course be sure to tell your mama that you're going to be cooking up the roast beef next
time you can show her how it's done
keep it real boys intent
and she
all right wrapped up pretty good
you do it the way
now we're going to throw these
four roasts on the grill or our
smoker this time right we've got our colossal
smoker and we're going to cook them couple of different
here we've got a roasting
pan it's
grated so it keeps it will keep it out of the juices underneath
we
we'll add the rest of that beef
broth in there this will add moisture to the entire smoker
right now
put our barbecue roast on
that and we've got four
of them now each one's going to cook at a different
temperature so that is
a problem you don't want to be checking the temperature with a with a chef's
thermometer or whatever a mechanical thermometer
the best way to do it is with one of these new digital thermometers we've been using these for a few years
this was given to us by our friends at grill
eye it's got six probes
you can use up to six on this
perfect
we're going to be able to monitor the temperature or internal temperature of all four
of these roasts and also one probe for the ambient temperature of the
smoker which should be about 275 degrees Fahrenheit
like I said low and slow
all
right all the probes have been inserted
nothing left to do now kick back
wait
all right we're about halfway through this
Lowe's and we're going to baste it
a bit gives us something to do between sixes
yeah
I just
can you smell that it smells good
there's nothing like roast beef on the grill right
and we'll throw some more barbecue sauce on that barbecue roast there
and wait
all right and
in a miracle of
time a couple of these wills had
done we've cooked them to about 120 degrees Fahrenheit internal
and that's rare for sure
but we're going to cover it with some
aluminum foil and the temperature will continue to
increase and get to our target temperature of about a 130 degrees Fahrenheit
which is about medium-rare
now
our alarm has gone off again and
our barbecue sauce roast is done
again we're going to pull
wrap it with some foil for at least a half
hour let it keep cooking and
yeah
now our pepper roast
is done of course this cooked a bit slower because it's double wrapped with aluminum foil
and we've got a temperature of about 115 degrees internal
we're pulling it off real rare and I'll show you why in a minute
now let me open this up so you can
we're about an hour and fifteen minutes maybe a little bit less
it's been steaming in those peppers and onions and garlic
hopeful lord have mercy
now the thing is this roast has been steamed and
it don't look very pretty now does
it so we pull it off the grill at a lower
temperature because we're going to finish it
off just straight on the
grill so we're going to pull it out of
place it on the
here I've made up some sauce I've
got some molasses and soy sauce
I want to give it some color and a little bit more flavor
use what you have
this is going to be good
this will probably take another 15 to 20 minutes or so to complete we
get our target temperature 125 to 130 somewhere in that range right
again
we use our probe to get that temperature perfect
all right
this one is done
cheap BBQ beef roast number four
pull it
I say darn near getting time to eat
all right this is the favorite part here
right cutting
you kidding
now you could serve up these anyway you want
maybe with mashed potatoes green beans and
but we're going to make a sandwich out
of these and we'll
get to that in a bit now what I want to show you is the moisture right
these are the two rows there are over that roasting
take a look at
full
of moisture cook perfectly medium-rare
and this is the only way you want
to serve these either rare or medium
rare or you're going to make
them too tough look at that moisture dripping
it melts
yeah
all right let's take a look at
the second one again done to perfection using this slow drilling method
look at a moisture
now the best way to slice
these roasts is to slice and very thin super thin
right if you got a meat cutter electric meat cutter or electric
knife use
it get these as
thin as you can that's the best way that's often the only way there
all right here's the barbecue
me show you what this looks like
again
is the moisture
even though we didn't inject this one
that
it's that the old temperature
the
basic get this
now last but not
cheap barbecue beef roast number four the pepper roast is
done it's been resting a bit more
let me show you what this looks like
I know this is the longest BBQ beef roast video
you've ever seen probably yes
but we're not going to fast
forward you're just going to keep going
now
that
baby
so I say tell your mama you're doing the roast is Sunday
we slice them again
perfect
now like I said you can serve these uh be froze up any
way you want but in this case we're going to make ourselves a big roast beef sandwich right
loaded with those roasted peppers
probably three pounds of beef
yeah
you do
load
you get hungry or what
all right
that some of them green bell peppers in
onions
and of course
you want to hit it with your drippings
we'll load it up with that great
listen
let's cut this sandwich up
take a look at that
you're not going to get that in the fast food
joint right and of course as always we do apologize greet in front
of you like this but we call this pitmaster privilege
the next time you're looking for a recipe for
your kid check out barbecue pit boys
duck